Shanfan HUANG, Curriculum Vitae

Personal Info

Profession Industrial and Strategic Designer

Website <u>shanfanhuang.com</u>

Expertise Information analysis; Communication design;

Strategic design; Industrial product design.

Language Chinese; English

Contact <u>shanfan.huang@gmail.com</u>, +358 44 5885017

Career Highlights

An ambitious designer who aims to integrate marketing and user insights into product development. Having had cross-fields experience in communication design and industrial design - the former closely related to marketing and the latter to R&D, I saw the inability of an external design consultant to take sufficient responsibility to influence the industrial chain. Therefore I joined Senseg, a technology startup company. As the only in-house designer I assist the CTO together with the R&D team to design the whole-package product concepts, and also with the CMO to shape the business strategy and product line.

Work Experience

2009-Now Senseg Oy, Helsinki	Industrial and Strategic Designer Pushing industrial design into product development by coordinating between Marketing/Sales and R&D team.
2008 Design Bridge, Amsterdam	Summer Intern Branding and packaging design
2007 Next Icon Oy, Helsinki	Website Consultant Consulting with <i>Next Icon</i> team on their company identity; Organizing the company portfolio; Copywriting marketing material; Website architecture.
2005 Sphere One Ltd. Shanghai	Junior Product Designer Assisting the senior transportation designer with his design concepts.
2003-2005 Black & White Drama Society, Hangzhou	Editorial Designer In charge of the marketing material of the drama society, including posters, flyers and brochures.
2004 Better Communication Ltd. Hangzhou	Freelance Graphic Designer Supplying Better Communication agency with illustration and graphic works.

Education

University of Art and Design, Helsinki
2006-2009 - Major in Industrial and Strategic Design

Master of Arts - Minor study in Media Lab

2002-2006 Zhejiang University, China

Bachelor of Engineering - Major in Industrial Design

Key Activities and Achievements

regretivities and remevements	
2009	Team Member of <u>Aalto Entrepreneurship Society</u> TAIK (University of Art and Design) Representative
2009	Social Media Concept Design for WHO Health Action in Crisis Media Lab – Marketing for International Development; Teamwork with Sebastian Greger and Jukka Purma
2008-2009	Master Thesis: World, Web, Word and the City Selected as <i>Students' Poster Showcase</i> and presented in <u>5th World Conference</u> on Mass Customization and Personalization
2007	Wallpaper Illustration for Sonera HQ Conference Room, Helsinki Selected from a Sonera-sponsored graphic design competition.
2007	First Prize of Philips Lumalive Product Concept Design School of Design cross-disciplinary project; Teamwork with Fabe Dalen (fashion designer) and Kalle Määttä (media designer)
2006	First Prize of TeliaSonera Branding Concept Design Business Lounge at Vantaa Airport, teamwork with Bing Su, Mina Park
2006	Merits Award of Liteon Industrial Design Award Immense Touch Concept Design, Teamwork with Huang Zhe
2005	Short Listed in Imagine the Home in 2020 Product design competition sponsored by Electrolux Design Lab; Teamwork with Lin Tao, Huang Zhe and Wang Zhuo